Guide to the Barry and Gloria Garfinkel Collection of Photographs 1946-1974 PR 382
New-York Historical Society
Barry and Gloria Garfinkel collection of photographs
1946-1974
New-York Historical Society
Garfinkel, Barry H., 1928-
PR 382
1 Linear feet in 1 box
This collection consists of 39 black and white photographs by various photographers. The photographs date from 1946-1974, and feature portraits of prominent people and New York City street scenes.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Barry and Gloria Garfinkel, 2017.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 39 black and white photographs by various photographers, including Victor Laredo, Fritz Henle, Arnold Eagle, Jill Freedman, Bruce Davidson, Jerry Lang, N. Jay Jaffee, Fons Ianelli, Fred McDarrah, Ken Regan, Ron Galella, and Arthur Leipzig. The photographs date from 1946-1974. Some photos feature portraits of prominent people, such as Truman Capote, Bella Abzug, John Cassavetes, and Diane Keaton. Other photos capture New York City street scenes, including police officers on the beat, children playing, iconic buildings, and views in Central Park.
Arrangement
The collection is aranged alphabetically by photographer.
Celebrities -- United States -- Portraits; Police -- New York (State) -- New York.; Street photography.
- Bruce Davidson, 1965 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Truman Capote promoting his novel "In Cold Blood" [3 photographs] (1965)
- Arnold Eagle, 1959-1964 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  Rehearsal for Mozart's "The Impresario" with Will Lee, Laura Bodnar, John Kuhn, and Arnold Gamson at the piano (1959).
  Exterior of 2 Columbus Circle, the Gallery of Modern Art, a.k.a. the Lollipop Building (1964).
- Jill Freedman, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  Four photographs of New York City police officers working their beats
  One photograph of a young tattooed man in a doorway
- Ron Galella, 1971 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  three photographs of Jackie Kennedy Onassis in Central Park, near the Reservoir, running from the photographer.
- Fritz Henle, 1946-1973 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  Bowery Concert [two women from a Bowery mission playing instruments on the street] (1946)
  Three photos of Alexander H. Cohen, theatrical producer (1973)
- Fons Ianelli, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  portrait of John Kiernan [American journalist]
- N. Jay Jaffee, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  5 photographs of unidentified landscapes; one image appears to be the boardwalk at Coney Island.
- Jerry Lang, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  Arthur Fiedler, conductor [2 portraits]
- Victor Laredo, 1948-1960 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  Central Park Interlude [pigeon landing on a man's hand] (1948)
  Central Park, New York [detail of carved stone staircase] (1960)
  East Harlem [kids playing in a vacant lot] (1952)
  Flatiron Building seen from Madison Square Park (1953)
- Arthur Leipzig, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  Question Mark Hopscotch, Blake Ave. Brooklyn [African American children playing]
- Fred McDarrah, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  Rabbi Samuel Blum.
- Ken Regan, 1974, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  Bella Abzug at City Hall on Women's Strike Day
  A.J. Antoon, play director [4 portraits]
  John Cassavetes directing the movie "Husbands" [on 8th Avenue and West 49th Street, 2 photos]
  Diane Keaton [in Central Park] (1974)